## INSTRUCTOR/TRAINER

Professional Summary

Collaborate well with clients on planning and implementation of systems. Over 20 years of technical experience in Retail, Banking and Investment Management. Skilled in business analysis and information technology. Function successfully with stakeholders. Knowledgeable in all stages of Business System life cycle development operations and metrics. Skills

- Database design
- · Excellent problemsolving abilities
- · Windows and

Linux

- Network maintenance
- System upgrades
- System backups
- Data backup and retrieval
- Brand
  - development
- Technical

Portfolio Asset Management

specifications creation

SystemTest case scenariosOperations managementMicrosoft Office SuiteCreativeAgileLinuxMS AccessSoftware

development lifecycle expertProject managementOperational analysisÂ

- Network upgrades · Remote access
  - technology
- Excellent communication skills
- QA tools
- Website maintenance
- · SQL and databases
- Data mapping

Work History

Instructor/Trainer, 01/2008 to 01/2012

Tsm â€" Tampa, FL

In a 3 ½ year period, taught and mentored 100s of high school students in Calculus, Algebra I, Algebra II, Geometry, Adobe Suite and Business Analysis Techniques

- Successfully improved student participation in the classroom through integration of creative role-playing exercises.
- Improved student's analytical skills by introducing state-of-the-art computer program technologies.

Business Analyst/Consultant, 01/2002 to 01/2014

Align Technology â€" Morrisville, PA

- Developed and implemented complex Internet and Intranet applications on multiple platforms.
- Coordinated with systems partners to finalize designs and confirm requirements.
- Provided continued maintenance and development of bug fixes and patch sets for existing web applications.
- Organized and created shooting schedules for graphic design team, supervising the progress of projects from production to post production.
- Consistently met deadlines and requirements for all production work orders.
- Managed creative projects from concept to completion while managing outside vendors.

Systems Analyst, 01/1990 to 01/1994

Nice Systems â€" San Jose, CA

- Developed and implemented complex Internet and Intranet applications on multiple platforms.
- Coordinated with systems partners to finalize designs and confirm requirements.
- Provided continued maintenance and development of bug fixes and patch sets for existing web applications.
- Organized and created shooting schedules for graphic design team, supervising the progress of projects from production to post production.
- Consistently met deadlines and requirements for all production work orders.
- Managed creative projects from concept to completion while managing outside vendors.

Software Engineer, 01/1994 to 01/2002

Adobe Systems Incorporated â€" Emeryville, CA

- Implemented user acceptance testing with a focus on documenting defects and executing test cases.
- Conducted interviews with key business users to collect information on business processes and user requirements.
- Wrote maintainable and extensible code in a team environment.
- Modified existing software to correct errors, upgrade interfaces and improve performance.
- Consulted regularly with customers on project status, proposals and technical issues.
- Prepared detailed reports concerning project specifications and activities.
- · Researched, designed and implemented scalable applications for information identification, extraction, analysis, retrieval and indexing,
- Interfaced with business analysts, developers and technical support to determine the best requirement specifications.

Purchasing Analyst, 01/1989 to 01/1990

Big Sea – Asheville , NC

- Develop and implement purchasing and contracts, policies, and procedures.
- Negotiate with vendors on materials, equipment or supplies, and interview them to determine product availability and terms of sales.

Trainer/Teacher, 2008 to 2014 NEISD â€" City, STATE

- Taught and mentored 100s of high school students in Calculus, Algebra I, Algebra II, Geometry, Adobe Suite and Microsoft products.
- Taught Graphic Design, Computer Animation and Business Analysis Techniques Investment Management Sector

Web Designer, 2002 to 2012 Avalta Solutioins â€" City, STATE

- Created custom websites with an attached database interface to track products.
- Designed data management monitoring and configured remote e-mail accounts.
- Purchasing Develop and implement purchasing and contracts, policies, and procedures.
- Negotiate with vendors on materials, equipment or supplies, and interview them to determine product availability and terms of sales.

## Education

Bachelor of Science : Computer Science , 1989 NORTHWESTERN STATE UNIVERSITY -

Computer Science

USAA Project Management: 1 2012

Associate of Arts: Business Administration, 1989

Northwestern State Univerity -

Affiliations

National Society of Black Engineers San Antonio Chapter Northwestern State University Alumni San Antonio Chapter San Antonio Chapter San Antonio Chapter San Antonio Chapter Oak Hills Church San Antonio, Crownridge Certifications

- Rackspace CloudÂ
  - USAA Project Management

## Associations

- National Society of Black Engineers Alumni Member
- Northwestern State University Alumni
- San Antonio Cares Executive Board
- Jack and Jill Program Director, Executive Board
- Oak Hills Church Member
- Girl Scouts Troop Leader

## Skills

ASP.NET, Adobe Suite, Adobe, Photoshop, Animation, Banking, budget, Business Analysis, Cash Register, Cobol, hardware upgrades, Hardware, contracts, Controller, Crystal Reports, CSS, data management, Databases, database, designing, Dreamweaver, e-mail, firewall, Fireworks, Flash, Graphic Design, HTML, Illustrator, Informix, Investment Management, JavaScript, Languages, Linux, Mac, materials, Microsoft products, MS Access, Windows, networking, Operating Systems, Oracle, policies, POS, printers, Project Management, Purchasing, Retail, Risk Management, routers, sales, SAS, Shell Scripts, Solaris, MS SQL Server, SQL, system design, Unix, upgrades, Utilities, Visio, Visual Basic, Visual Studio, Web Development, websites